<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-12-29T09:54:43-06:00</updated><id>https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DMP in ATX</title><subtitle>The incredibly nerdy blog of Dustin Pfannenstiel, social media ex-pat.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Rise of Skywalker</title><link href="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/12/24/rise_of_skywalker.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rise of Skywalker" /><published>2019-12-24T10:47:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-12-24T10:47:00-06:00</updated><id>https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/12/24/rise_of_skywalker</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/12/24/rise_of_skywalker.html">&lt;p&gt;For two-and-a-half-hours last night I was nine years old again.
I sat in rapt attention next to my dad as the fanfare boomed from the speakers and The Words in yellow lettering scrolled into the distance.
The nonology now known as the &lt;em&gt;Skywalker Saga&lt;/em&gt; has reached its conclusion, 42 years after it began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d be a fool to call the “the last &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; film” as though it was going to be the last film to ever feature the Jedi.
But, we are told that we’ve seen the last of the Skywalkers and I’m choosing to believe that.
And for purposes of this post, “the last &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; film” will do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, spoilers abound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;trepidation&quot;&gt;Trepidation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had some concern when J.J. Abrams was announced as the director of Episode IX.
I still have a sour taste in my mouth from his &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt; reboot.
&lt;em&gt;The Force Awakens&lt;/em&gt; was a fine film, but where it was weak was in all the things J.J. is known for.
He has a habit of setting up a mythology and not knowing how he’s going to pay it off.
Rather than having a plan, you end up with having to squeeze the plot into one of the holes you’ve dug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please see Season 8 of Game of Thrones for an excellent example of what happens when you’re not prepared to pay off a long running plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; is famous for is that scene in &lt;em&gt;Empire&lt;/em&gt; where Vader reveals to Luke who is father is.
Prior to that moment, we had spent almost two whole movies blissfully believing that Luke’s dad was this fighter pilot and Jedi.
Just an all around froody dude who fought on the side of good and always knew where his towel was (that last bit isn’t exactly canon).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn’t need any more than that.
&lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; was a fairly simple space opera.
Good vs. evil.
The whole shebang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By adding that one moment, at the right time, &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; suddenly became legendary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going into the sequel trilogy, &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; came with baggage.
And it was baggage of our own making.
We decided everything needed to connect, everything needed meaning.
And it really doesn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Force Awakens&lt;/em&gt; works perfectly as a movie if you edit out any vague references to Rey’s parentage.
It’s barely in there anyway.
Most of the hype around it is due to publicity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, because of the baggage brought by the Fandom, people started asking “who is Snoke”?
He doesn’t need to be anyone.
He never needed to be anyone.
He just needed to be the bad guy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rian Johnson did everyone a huge favor by saying, “Rey’s parentage is a pointless distraction and Kylo Ren is the real bad guy of this series.  Let’s move on.”
I didn’t need a redemption arc for Kylo Ren; I assumed by the end of &lt;em&gt;The Last Jedi&lt;/em&gt; he was beyond redemption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reconciliation&quot;&gt;Reconciliation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaving &lt;em&gt;The Rise of Skywalker&lt;/em&gt; I felt incredibly satisfied.
There were three specific complaints I had:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Kiss - when did this suddenly become a love story? This was totally unneeded, out of place, and confusing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rey’s Parentage - Re edit this film to remove any reference to her parentage and watch it work perfectly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Ticking Clock - Travel times in &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; have always been loose, but the ticking clock in this movie and &lt;em&gt;The Last Jedi&lt;/em&gt; were just dumb.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went into this movie expecting an epic show down of good versus evil and I got it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In spades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-cameos---a-love-letter&quot;&gt;The Cameos - A Love Letter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had assumed that “Force Ghost Luke” would end up playing a larger role in this movie, but he was just right.
Just a tour around the galaxy of the Old Jedi.
The final “Rise” sequence featured almost every Jedi ever captured on screen.
Including Hayden Christensen and James Earl Jones.
Despite the fact that they play the same person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ian McDiarmid managed to play the Emperor at his very creepiest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Leia work was amazing.
I know they had to work off of existing footage of Carrie Fisher and I thought they did a fantastic job of incorporating her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brining back Billie Dee Williams as Lando was a nice touch.
As was the return of Denis Lawson as fan favorite Wedge Antilles.
If you’ve never heard of Wedge Antilles, that’s okay.
But for reference he was the only non main character to survive all three original &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; films.
Including both Death Star battles.
For the big fans, the three seconds of screen time he got at the end were a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The uncredited return of Harrison Ford was a nice touch as well.
He played &amp;lt;/checks notes&amp;gt; Han Solo.
This movie needed to provide a final, absoulute bit of closure to the fans and after it settles a bit, I think that’s the thing that will do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-battles---epic&quot;&gt;The Battles - Epic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing about the final movie in a series this epic is that everyone is on the table.
Killing Rey midway through the picture?
Completely possible.
When they killed Chewie, I 100% believed that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lightsaber duel was the best they’ve ever done.
Better than the Duel of Fates.
I literally watch the Duel of Fates the night before and it’s not even close.
Watching Rey and Kylo go after each other in that environment was intense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding to it all is that you really don’t know how that one was going to end.
Kylo could have won.
Rey could have turned to the Dark Side.
There are any number of ways that could have broken down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Possibly the lasting element of &lt;em&gt;The Last Jedi&lt;/em&gt; was the establishment that Rey and Ren can pass physical objects when communicating.
Passing the lightsaber was a fantastic turn.
The payoff was great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-star-wars&quot;&gt;The Star Wars&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been really happy with the new trilogy.
I read joke a couple of years ago:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Do you know what the worst part of &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; is?
The fans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to like everything to like these movies.
My whole life I’ve loved &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; knowing there were parts that were dumb, but that’s never made me love them any less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That doesn’t hold true for the prequels, but no one is going to fault me for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m looking forward to seeing what happens next.
Rian Johnson, gave us a &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; that had a bit more hope in it than the rest of the new trilogy.
That’s a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got to go see a &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; movie with my dad.
And that made it a pretty good day.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Musings and reflections on the conclusion of the Skywalker Saga.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Merry Christmas, Ya Filthy Animal</title><link href="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/12/23/merry-christmas-ya-filthy-animal.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Merry Christmas, Ya Filthy Animal" /><published>2019-12-23T10:47:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-12-23T10:47:00-06:00</updated><id>https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/12/23/merry-christmas-ya-filthy-animal</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/12/23/merry-christmas-ya-filthy-animal.html">&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;/stretches&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/yawns&amp;gt;
Oh, my.
What per chance could this be?
A blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess it’s been a minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re about to go take my father to see the final film of the Skywaker Saga.
Amazing that he’s been watching &lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; films for 42 years.
What do you know.
42.
The answer to life, the universe, and everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been the year where time has marched on.
I turned 40.
And otherwise… same as it ever was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have cleared down from Facebook.
One last holiday and then that’s ready to get blowed up real good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been a few adventures in the past few months.
Maybe I’ll take the time to write some of those up.
Mostly I need to be sure the build system is still working.
&amp;lt;/nerd&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now: Merry Christmas to you and yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be Well.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">2019 is coming to a close and this blog proably deserves an update.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Done But Not Done Done</title><link href="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/04/27/done-but-not-done-done.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Done But Not Done Done" /><published>2019-04-27T21:47:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-04-27T21:47:00-05:00</updated><id>https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/04/27/done-but-not-done-done</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/04/27/done-but-not-done-done.html">&lt;p&gt;My skin is warm.
My muscles … they don’t ache, but they tingle.
A low, dull throbbing resonates throughout my entire body.
And I have that heat behind my eyes.
The kind you get when you know you have a fever coming on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m probably not sick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s become difficult to tell.
A lot of the past few months has been so “go-go-go” that it’s become hard to tell the difference between sick and tired.
I’m just tired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent all morning in the garden.
One of the many things I had been putting off for months was weeding and cleaning up the front garden.
It had begun … no, that’s false.
It had been looking bad for a while.
I there had just been too many other things to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving into a house is a big deal.
I’m still not “Done Done”.
But the list is smaller.
The items getting put into the backlog are manageable and understood.
There’s some success in that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mere fact that I’m worried about “Done Done” is nice.
It means that the necessary and proper is complete.
I know there’s more to do and I’ll do it, but those are things that can be pushed later.
At least a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to make a list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can spend a bit more time on the things I want.
This blog for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, I’ve had to admit that I’ve been doing too much and had to drop some stuff.
I canceled Family Meal at game.
It was just too much.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When you push past the point of tired into exhaustion it's time to stop for a hot minute. For me that minute is now.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dusting Off</title><link href="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/04/08/dusting-off.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dusting Off" /><published>2019-04-08T21:20:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-04-08T21:20:00-05:00</updated><id>https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/04/08/dusting-off</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/04/08/dusting-off.html">&lt;p&gt;Last month or so has been a bit of a grind.
Been suffering a little bit of burnout.
It’s been a challenge to get to the gym.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last couple of days, though, it feels like I’ve turned a corner.
I finally got those pictures hung.
I should probably post pictures of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, I also got a new build system for this blog.
And I’m really happy about that.
In case it’s not clear.
This is a test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be well.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Clearing out the cob-webs a bit.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">March In Retrospect</title><link href="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/04/07/march-in-retrospect.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="March In Retrospect" /><published>2019-04-07T08:37:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-04-07T08:37:00-05:00</updated><id>https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/04/07/march-in-retrospect</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/04/07/march-in-retrospect.html">&lt;p&gt;Winter is finally over.
At long freaking last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A long weekend found me in San Antonio, there to take The Boy to see &lt;em&gt;Captain Marvel&lt;/em&gt;.
I wanted one thing, and one thing only, from this movie.
For the cat to take the eye.
And I got it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we’ll call that a success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark planned the whole thing, which was wonderful.
We visited the Alamo and it a couple of the tourist traps in the area.
If you ever have an opportunity to visit a &lt;em&gt;Mirror Maze&lt;/em&gt; I recommend it.
They’re pretty trippy.
You never know if the person ahead of you is really ahead of you.
It did give me the opportunity to reach out and grab Mark he thought I was just a reflection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The week after, The Boy turned 19.
I spend about six hours attempting to paper craft a box to put a check in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how I amuse myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that wasn’t my last project.
I then, finally, turned myself towards the kitchen table.
With some instruction from my parents I sanded that sucker down and refinished it.
I should write a longer post about that with pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alas, I neglected to take the before shots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in case it’s unclear, the purpose of this post is to test out a new build system.
So that all for now.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Two and a half months since my last post... that's talent.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Glass - Reviewed</title><link href="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/01/20/glass-reviewed.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Glass - Reviewed" /><published>2019-01-20T17:37:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-01-20T17:37:00-06:00</updated><id>https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/01/20/glass---reviewed</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/01/20/glass-reviewed.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spoilers Abound&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-little-history&quot;&gt;A Little History&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full disclosure, I didn’t like &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0217869/&quot;&gt;Unbreakable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; when it first came out.
M. Night Shyamalan was just coming off &lt;em&gt;The Sixth Sense&lt;/em&gt; and had to do another “twist ending film”.
It felt cheap.
I thought the constant refernces to comic books were a bit too meta.
It was dark.
Way darker than most films I was watching at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were some very human moments.
The scene where Joseph get’s David to put a dangerous amount of weight on the barbell… I can see anyone’s dad doing that.
Elijah Price kicking a paying customer out when it was discovered that he was purchasing art for his kids bedroom.
Also, very human to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took years and mutliple viewings for me to start liking this film.
Somewhere, someone pointed out that if the ending gets moved to the middle, then we get realistic superhero films five years before &lt;em&gt;Batman Begins&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt4972582/&quot;&gt;Split&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; came out, I missed it entirely.
I like James McAvoy.
Serial killer films are generally interesting.
I was in the middle of an “everything sucks” period.
I just missed it.
I didn’t even realize it was M. Night Shyamalan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I heard good things.
Then I heard there was a killer, amazing, spectacular post credits scene.
Then my nephew spilled the beans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I was intrigued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat down and watched it and was amazed.
It was gripping.
Well written.
McAvoy brought depth and emotion to each of the alters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was hooked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, oh my God, there was going to be a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt6823368/&quot;&gt;thrid&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;generally-positive&quot;&gt;Generally Positive&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note to self: come up with a matrix for evaluating these films.  Ordinal values are bullshit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to talk about the two things I disliked first.
Let’s get that out of the way before moving on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The early part of the second act drags a bit.
The meta-humans (I know it’s a DC thing, you come up with a better name!) have been captured, there’s this ticking clock, but not a lot is happening.
A great deal is being done to describe the elaborate means being used to contained the trio, however even the Checkov’s rifles set up don’t quite justify it.
The film never really develops a sense of what’s a stake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second thing that bothered me was the &lt;em&gt;deus ex machina&lt;/em&gt; tidying things up at the end.
This was another, frankly needless, twist ending.
I think there’s any number of ways to have writting that ending to have killed all three meta-humans with a bit more satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the journey isn’t the destination…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The writing treats the viewers with a lot of respect.
We’re re-introduced to David’s world without a lot of exposition.
He’s a guy; he’s got a business; his kid still worships him.
You don’t need much more than that.
Anything else that you need you can pick up through contextual clues or as relevant to the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The relationship between Kevin and Casey was kind of sweet and wonderful.
This was another place where the actors and writer/director just let the context of the story work.
You didn’t need to know much about their history to know that they were important to each other.
Casey genuinely seemed to want to save Kevin from the Horde the way he saved her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also really liked how they intertwined the lives of Casey and Joseph.
From going to the same school to the same comic book store.
In a world where the relationships between characters was so important, it kept me on the edge of my seat wondering when and how they’d meet.
But I have to admit, thinking back, I can’t remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One, last standout thing to bring up is Sarah Paulson.
Amazing as ever.
The plot kept her aloof, but she moved between matronly and stern as needed quite adeptly.
Her make-up was outstanding.
The monochromatic hair with flat, matt skin, and deeply contrasting lipstick made her seem more like a comic book character than anyone else in the film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess that’s appropriate since it was her origin story.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The coda to the Eastrail 177 Trilogy has been one of non-Marvel, non-Star Wars films I've been awaiting most fervently. Let's see how it stacks up.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Looking Good Far From Home</title><link href="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/01/15/looking-good-far-from-home.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Looking Good Far From Home" /><published>2019-01-15T17:06:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-01-15T17:06:00-06:00</updated><id>https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/01/15/looking-good-far-from-home</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/01/15/looking-good-far-from-home.html">&lt;p&gt;Maybe it’s because I’m deep inside the 2018 &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt; video game, but I instantly fell in love with this trailer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breaking it down, there were five major elements on display.
How big those elements end up being to the film are anyone’s guess, but they do feature prominently in the trailer.
Out of my fandom for &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DOB_INC&quot;&gt;DOB&lt;/a&gt; and Cracked let’s listicle this sucker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-overseas-trip&quot;&gt;5. Overseas Trip&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, the Academic Decathon team is going over seas for reasons.
Staying in hostels or what have you.
Looks like the trip of a life time for young Peter … were he not Spider-man.
His insistence a leaving his suit, despite May’s suggestion, behind might be a red herring; a trick of editing.
There’s not much here, it set’s the scene for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-nick-fury&quot;&gt;4. Nick Fury&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samuel L. Jackson is the fourth most interesting thing about this trailer.
Let that sink in for a moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fourth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks like he’s recruiting Spidey for some blah, blah, blah, new suit, blah, blah, blah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fourth.
Most.
Intersting.
Thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-new-mj&quot;&gt;3. New MJ&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MJ was one of my favorite parts about &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man: Homecoming&lt;/em&gt;.
I’ll cover that more when I write it up before &lt;em&gt;Avengers: Endgame&lt;/em&gt;, but I enjoyed watching her toy with Peter here.
It was a nice change from the portrayals we’ve seen of MJ in the past and I fully support it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-happy-and-aunt-may&quot;&gt;2. Happy and Aunt May&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hot Aunt May” was a nice bit in &lt;em&gt;Civil War&lt;/em&gt;.
And I was glad they carried it through to &lt;em&gt;Homecoming&lt;/em&gt;.
Frankly, I’d love to see May, Tony, and Pepper in a scene together where Pepper starts getting possessive about Tony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Happy and May bit was just exciting.
Not merely because I like the running gag, but because I’m kind of pulling for Happy here.
He doesn’t have much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His job?
As Iron Man’s body guard?
It would be nice to see him settle down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m shipping these two.
Is there a petition I can sign?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-mysterio&quot;&gt;1. Mysterio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not a Spider-Man fan (sorry Daniel, who totally reads this).
I don’t know the first thing about the comics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I do know a little about movies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re not shooting Mysterio like a villian.
He’s pretty.
He’s showing his face.
He’s defending the little people.
He’s got broad shoulders and is fighting a monster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s a hero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least, that’s how he sees it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember the thing someone said about Shrek, “every villian is the hero of their own story.”
That looks exactly like what they’re doing to Mysterio.
Sure, it sets up a trope for “friends become enemies,” but that’s okay sometimes.
Given everything else they’ve done in the MCU, they’ll probably nail it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess we’ll find out in July.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The first film of Phase 4 (or whatever we're calling it) has dropped. And it looks lovely.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">We’re In The Endgame Now</title><link href="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/12/16/we're-in-the-endgame-now.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We're In The Endgame Now" /><published>2018-12-16T07:59:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-12-16T07:59:00-06:00</updated><id>https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/12/16/we're-in-the-endgame-now</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/12/16/we're-in-the-endgame-now.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A man needs a name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, we finally have a name.  I forget who said it first.  I think it was my brother; he thinks it was me.  Regardless, neither of us was terribly surprised at the title &lt;em&gt;Avengers: Endgame&lt;/em&gt; given Dr. Strange’s line from &lt;em&gt;Infinity War&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still have &amp;lt;checks watch&amp;gt; four months until the film actully comes out so there will be plenty of time to prognisticate (badly).  Let’s concentrate on what we do know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, YouTube embed’s are terrible and I wish Google wasn’t so controlling.  Their “Don’t Be Evil” corporate motto is bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, we’ve got Tony in space on Star Lord’s ship, now called the &lt;em&gt;Benetar&lt;/em&gt; I hear, dropping a message to Pepper.  It’s a saccharin sweet moment designed to tug at the heart strings.  The Ironman suits have become something of a joke in my house &lt;strong&gt;Because Of Reasons&lt;/strong&gt; and my brother pointed out that it’s weird that the nano tech is still holding together like it’s a physical mask… but I digress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanos seems to have a happy life.  He’s got his little Thanos Armor Scarecrow that I look forward to seeing popping up at Cons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the voice over starts, I get a sense that Black Widow and Steve are going to be carrying this movie.  Of the Avengers up to this point, these are the two characters that have lost the most in their lives.  They’re the ones use to suffering at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hawkeye as “Ronin” (my nephew assures me) looks awesome.  There’s a strong sense that time has between &lt;em&gt;Infinity War&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Endgame&lt;/em&gt;, maybe as much as five years.  If that’s the case I desperately want to know what happened to Clint in this time, because he does not look like a well man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there’s Scott.  Everyone’s shocked to see Scott is back. I think that’s big.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Phase 4 of the MCU is about to wrap up.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stranger Things Continue</title><link href="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/12/14/stranger-things-season-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stranger Things Continue" /><published>2018-12-14T17:48:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-12-14T17:48:00-06:00</updated><id>https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/12/14/stranger-things-season-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/12/14/stranger-things-season-3.html">&lt;p&gt;The teaser trailer for &lt;em&gt;Stranger Things&lt;/em&gt; Season 3 dropped and it sure lives up to it’s name as a “tease”.
When the music started playing my brother heard it from the next room and shouted, “Is that ‘Stranger Things’,” before coming over to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All it told us, presumeably, was the title of the eight episodes of season 3.
If you’ve seen season 2 and have lived on the internet at all you can probably take a guess at some of the things going on in these episodes.
And I will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Suzie, Do You Copy?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This title is interesting just because it’s so different from the rest of the titles.  I think this ties back to “Starcourt” in the last episode.  Maybe a RPG character is the titular Suzie.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Mall Rats
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Everyone is still too young to have a job, but malls are a place to have some independence.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Case of the Missing Lifeguard&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Sauna Test
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Some sort of insane endurance test in a sauna to prove they’re not infected from the upside down.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Source
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Eleven has a sister of sorts.  I think she’s been setup to be the Big Bad of season three.  I bet this is where the Party finds that out.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Birthday&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Bite&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Battle of Starcourt
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A lot of &lt;em&gt;Stranger Things&lt;/em&gt; mythos comes from D&amp;amp;D, “Starcourt” will be their analogue to explain something.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose we’ll find out eventually.  As the trailer promises…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the summer of 1985,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The adventure continues…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Coming 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The trailer for stranger things dropped and it's every bit as frustrating as you can imagine.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Technical Debt and the Last Jedi</title><link href="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/01/08/technical-debt-last-jedi.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Technical Debt and the Last Jedi" /><published>2018-01-08T13:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-08T13:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/01/08/technical-debt-last-jedi</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/01/08/technical-debt-last-jedi.html">&lt;p&gt;Note: Spoilers throughout this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Star Wars: The Last Jedi&lt;/em&gt; has been out for a few weeks now to mixed reviews.  Most people I know disliked the film.  My brother is pretty ambivalent about it, which I guess I understand.  I have less understanding for the people who outright dislike it.  Adam Savage’s podcast “Still Untitled” had a wonderful &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/last-jedi-spoilercast-still-untitled-adam-savage-project/id586730504?i=1000397863360&amp;amp;mt=2&quot;&gt;review of the film&lt;/a&gt;.  I’ll try not repeat him too much, but I believe it was there that I did hear someone say, “&lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; was always a children’s film”.  I like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me start with what I disliked.  First, foremost, and eternally: The Pod Racer Scene.  ”What pod racer scene?” I can hear you asking through the aether.  The Pod Racer Scene.  The pointless, cutesy chase scene in the middle of the movie because someone decided that a jail break wasn’t enough action.  It did nothing for the movie and the run time certainly didn’t need it.  The second thing was the conflict generated by the fleet only having 18 hours of fuel.  I understand the role that ticking clocks can have in generating tension in film.  This scenario just didn’t make sense.  I’m willing to forgive the question about where the rest of the Imp- First Order fleet was.  I can even explain away the inability to micro jump.  18 hours doesn’t seem nearly enough time for Finn and Rose to go find this computer guy and bring him back.  I know hyper speed is faster than warp drive, it just doesn’t seem reasonable that they could have ever expected to fulfill the mission and get back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now lets leave the negativity behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought &lt;em&gt;The Last Jedi&lt;/em&gt; was a stunningly beautiful film.  In particular, having the star cruiser hyper speed through Snoke’s command ship was amazing to watch.  Rian Johnson’s decision to cut audio was inspired.  Imp- First Order crafts have never had such a sense of depth as when Finn and Rose infiltrated it.  Similarly, Snoke’s chamber provided a intimidating, alien environment that echoed the intensity of the Luke and Vader duel in the Cloud City Carbonite Chamber in &lt;em&gt;Empire&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Johnson’s writing powered the saga forward by ignoring as much of the J.J. Abrams setup as they possibly could.  Revealing Rey’s parentage to be completely unimportant was the best possible outcome, any other decision would have been seen as servicing some strange corner of the fandom (though, maybe if we didn’t spend so much time obsessing about it, the writers could just write).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The execution of Snoke by Kylo Ren set up the concluding film nicely while paying off two more plot points.  The first being the identity of Snoke.  Once again, not everything needs to be something else.  He didn’t need to be a previous Sith Lord.  All he had to be was evil: Mission Accomplished!  Finally, where are the Knights of Ren?  What are the Knights of Ren?  They’re just gone now.  No need to even bring them up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
	Parameters:
		content - the text
		type - optional type information
		title - optional title information
--&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;post_script alert&quot;&gt;
	
		&lt;div class=&quot;box-header&quot;&gt;
			Post Script
		&lt;/div&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&quot;alert_content&quot;&gt;
		
I was so very, very wrong in my last post.  Really missed the mark.

	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A poorly written review of The Last Jedi. Hashtag salesmanship.</summary></entry></feed>