<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-04-07T11:09:38-05:00</updated><id>https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DMP in ATX</title><subtitle>The incredibly nerdy blog of Dustin Pfannenstiel, social media ex-pat.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Glass - Reviewed</title><link href="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/01/20/glass-reviewed.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Glass - Reviewed" /><published>2019-01-20T17:37:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-01-20T17:37:00-06:00</updated><id>https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/01/20/glass---reviewed</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/01/20/glass-reviewed.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Spoilers Abound&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-little-history&quot;&gt;A Little History&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full disclosure, I didn’t like &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0217869/&quot;&gt;Unbreakable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; when it first came out.
M. Night Shyamalan was just coming off &lt;em&gt;The Sixth Sense&lt;/em&gt; and had to do another “twist ending film”.
It felt cheap.
I thought the constant refernces to comic books were a bit too meta.
It was dark.
Way darker than most films I was watching at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were some very human moments.
The scene where Joseph get’s David to put a dangerous amount of weight on the barbell… I can see anyone’s dad doing that.
Elijah Price kicking a paying customer out when it was discovered that he was purchasing art for his kids bedroom.
Also, very human to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took years and mutliple viewings for me to start liking this film.
Somewhere, someone pointed out that if the ending gets moved to the middle, then we get realistic superhero films five years before &lt;em&gt;Batman Begins&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt4972582/&quot;&gt;Split&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; came out, I missed it entirely.
I like James McAvoy.
Serial killer films are generally interesting.
I was in the middle of an “everything sucks” period.
I just missed it.
I didn’t even realize it was M. Night Shyamalan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I heard good things.
Then I heard there was a killer, amazing, spectacular post credits scene.
Then my nephew spilled the beans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I was intrigued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat down and watched it and was amazed.
It was gripping.
Well written.
McAvoy brought depth and emotion to each of the alters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was hooked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, oh my God, there was going to be a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt6823368/&quot;&gt;thrid&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;generally-positive&quot;&gt;Generally Positive&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note to self: come up with a matrix for evaluating these films.  Ordinal values are bullshit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to talk about the two things I disliked first.
Let’s get that out of the way before moving on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The early part of the second act drags a bit.
The meta-humans (I know it’s a DC thing, you come up with a better name!) have been captured, there’s this ticking clock, but not a lot is happening.
A great deal is being done to describe the elaborate means being used to contained the trio, however even the Checkov’s rifles set up don’t quite justify it.
The film never really develops a sense of what’s a stake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second thing that bothered me was the &lt;em&gt;deus ex machina&lt;/em&gt; tidying things up at the end.
This was another, frankly needless, twist ending.
I think there’s any number of ways to have writting that ending to have killed all three meta-humans with a bit more satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the journey isn’t the destination…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The writing treats the viewers with a lot of respect.
We’re re-introduced to David’s world without a lot of exposition.
He’s a guy; he’s got a business; his kid still worships him.
You don’t need much more than that.
Anything else that you need you can pick up through contextual clues or as relevant to the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The relationship between Kevin and Casey was kind of sweet and wonderful.
This was another place where the actors and writer/director just let the context of the story work.
You didn’t need to know much about their history to know that they were important to each other.
Casey genuinely seemed to want to save Kevin from the Horde the way he saved her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also really liked how they intertwined the lives of Casey and Joseph.
From going to the same school to the same comic book store.
In a world where the relationships between characters was so important, it kept me on the edge of my seat wondering when and how they’d meet.
But I have to admit, thinking back, I can’t remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One, last standout thing to bring up is Sarah Paulson.
Amazing as ever.
The plot kept her aloof, but she moved between matronly and stern as needed quite adeptly.
Her make-up was outstanding.
The monochromatic hair with flat, matt skin, and deeply contrasting lipstick made her seem more like a comic book character than anyone else in the film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess that’s appropriate since it was her origin story.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The coda to the Eastrail 177 Trilogy has been one of non-Marvel, non-Star Wars films I've been awaiting most fervently. Let's see how it stacks up.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Looking Good Far From Home</title><link href="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/01/15/looking-good-far-from-home.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Looking Good Far From Home" /><published>2019-01-15T17:06:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-01-15T17:06:00-06:00</updated><id>https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/01/15/looking-good-far-from-home</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2019/01/15/looking-good-far-from-home.html">&lt;p&gt;Maybe it’s because I’m deep inside the 2018 &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man&lt;/em&gt; video game, but I instantly fell in love with this trailer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breaking it down, there were five major elements on display.
How big those elements end up being to the film are anyone’s guess, but they do feature prominently in the trailer.
Out of my fandom for &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DOB_INC&quot;&gt;DOB&lt;/a&gt; and Cracked let’s listicle this sucker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-overseas-trip&quot;&gt;5. Overseas Trip&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, the Academic Decathon team is going over seas for reasons.
Staying in hostels or what have you.
Looks like the trip of a life time for young Peter … were he not Spider-man.
His insistence a leaving his suit, despite May’s suggestion, behind might be a red herring; a trick of editing.
There’s not much here, it set’s the scene for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-nick-fury&quot;&gt;4. Nick Fury&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samuel L. Jackson is the fourth most interesting thing about this trailer.
Let that sink in for a moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fourth.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks like he’s recruiting Spidey for some blah, blah, blah, new suit, blah, blah, blah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fourth.
Most.
Intersting.
Thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-new-mj&quot;&gt;3. New MJ&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MJ was one of my favorite parts about &lt;em&gt;Spider-Man: Homecoming&lt;/em&gt;.
I’ll cover that more when I write it up before &lt;em&gt;Avengers: Endgame&lt;/em&gt;, but I enjoyed watching her toy with Peter here.
It was a nice change from the portrayals we’ve seen of MJ in the past and I fully support it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-happy-and-aunt-may&quot;&gt;2. Happy and Aunt May&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hot Aunt May” was a nice bit in &lt;em&gt;Civil War&lt;/em&gt;.
And I was glad they carried it through to &lt;em&gt;Homecoming&lt;/em&gt;.
Frankly, I’d love to see May, Tony, and Pepper in a scene together where Pepper starts getting possessive about Tony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Happy and May bit was just exciting.
Not merely because I like the running gag, but because I’m kind of pulling for Happy here.
He doesn’t have much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His job?
As Iron Man’s body guard?
It would be nice to see him settle down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m shipping these two.
Is there a petition I can sign?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-mysterio&quot;&gt;1. Mysterio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not a Spider-Man fan (sorry Daniel, who totally reads this).
I don’t know the first thing about the comics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I do know a little about movies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re not shooting Mysterio like a villian.
He’s pretty.
He’s showing his face.
He’s defending the little people.
He’s got broad shoulders and is fighting a monster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He’s a hero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least, that’s how he sees it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember the thing someone said about Shrek, “every villian is the hero of their own story.”
That looks exactly like what they’re doing to Mysterio.
Sure, it sets up a trope for “friends become enemies,” but that’s okay sometimes.
Given everything else they’ve done in the MCU, they’ll probably nail it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess we’ll find out in July.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The first film of Phase 4 (or whatever we're calling it) has dropped. And it looks lovely.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">We’re In The Endgame Now</title><link href="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/12/16/we're-in-the-endgame-now.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We're In The Endgame Now" /><published>2018-12-16T07:59:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-12-16T07:59:00-06:00</updated><id>https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/12/16/we're-in-the-endgame-now</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/12/16/we're-in-the-endgame-now.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A man needs a name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, we finally have a name.  I forget who said it first.  I think it was my brother; he thinks it was me.  Regardless, neither of us was terribly surprised at the title &lt;em&gt;Avengers: Endgame&lt;/em&gt; given Dr. Strange’s line from &lt;em&gt;Infinity War&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still have &amp;lt;checks watch&amp;gt; four months until the film actully comes out so there will be plenty of time to prognisticate (badly).  Let’s concentrate on what we do know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, YouTube embed’s are terrible and I wish Google wasn’t so controlling.  Their “Don’t Be Evil” corporate motto is bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, we’ve got Tony in space on Star Lord’s ship, now called the &lt;em&gt;Benetar&lt;/em&gt; I hear, dropping a message to Pepper.  It’s a saccharin sweet moment designed to tug at the heart strings.  The Ironman suits have become something of a joke in my house &lt;strong&gt;Because Of Reasons&lt;/strong&gt; and my brother pointed out that it’s weird that the nano tech is still holding together like it’s a physical mask… but I digress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanos seems to have a happy life.  He’s got his little Thanos Armor Scarecrow that I look forward to seeing popping up at Cons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the voice over starts, I get a sense that Black Widow and Steve are going to be carrying this movie.  Of the Avengers up to this point, these are the two characters that have lost the most in their lives.  They’re the ones use to suffering at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hawkeye as “Ronin” (my nephew assures me) looks awesome.  There’s a strong sense that time has between &lt;em&gt;Infinity War&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Endgame&lt;/em&gt;, maybe as much as five years.  If that’s the case I desperately want to know what happened to Clint in this time, because he does not look like a well man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there’s Scott.  Everyone’s shocked to see Scott is back. I think that’s big.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Phase 4 of the MCU is about to wrap up.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stranger Things Continue</title><link href="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/12/14/stranger-things-season-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stranger Things Continue" /><published>2018-12-14T17:48:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-12-14T17:48:00-06:00</updated><id>https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/12/14/stranger-things-season-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/12/14/stranger-things-season-3.html">&lt;p&gt;The teaser trailer for &lt;em&gt;Stranger Things&lt;/em&gt; Season 3 dropped and it sure lives up to it’s name as a “tease”.
When the music started playing my brother heard it from the next room and shouted, “Is that ‘Stranger Things’,” before coming over to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All it told us, presumeably, was the title of the eight episodes of season 3.
If you’ve seen season 2 and have lived on the internet at all you can probably take a guess at some of the things going on in these episodes.
And I will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Suzie, Do You Copy?
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This title is interesting just because it’s so different from the rest of the titles.  I think this ties back to “Starcourt” in the last episode.  Maybe a RPG character is the titular Suzie.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Mall Rats
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Everyone is still too young to have a job, but malls are a place to have some independence.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Case of the Missing Lifeguard&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Sauna Test
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Some sort of insane endurance test in a sauna to prove they’re not infected from the upside down.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Source
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Eleven has a sister of sorts.  I think she’s been setup to be the Big Bad of season three.  I bet this is where the Party finds that out.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Birthday&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Bite&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Battle of Starcourt
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A lot of &lt;em&gt;Stranger Things&lt;/em&gt; mythos comes from D&amp;amp;D, “Starcourt” will be their analogue to explain something.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suppose we’ll find out eventually.  As the trailer promises…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the summer of 1985,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The adventure continues…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Coming 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The trailer for stranger things dropped and it's every bit as frustrating as you can imagine.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Technical Debt and the Last Jedi</title><link href="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/01/08/technical-debt-last-jedi.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Technical Debt and the Last Jedi" /><published>2018-01-08T13:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-08T13:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/01/08/technical-debt-last-jedi</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/01/08/technical-debt-last-jedi.html">&lt;p&gt;Note: Spoilers throughout this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Star Wars: The Last Jedi&lt;/em&gt; has been out for a few weeks now to mixed reviews.  Most people I know disliked the film.  My brother is pretty ambivalent about it, which I guess I understand.  I have less understanding for the people who outright dislike it.  Adam Savage’s podcast “Still Untitled” had a wonderful &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/last-jedi-spoilercast-still-untitled-adam-savage-project/id586730504?i=1000397863360&amp;amp;mt=2&quot;&gt;review of the film&lt;/a&gt;.  I’ll try not repeat him too much, but I believe it was there that I did hear someone say, “&lt;em&gt;Star Wars&lt;/em&gt; was always a children’s film”.  I like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me start with what I disliked.  First, foremost, and eternally: The Pod Racer Scene.  ”What pod racer scene?” I can hear you asking through the aether.  The Pod Racer Scene.  The pointless, cutesy chase scene in the middle of the movie because someone decided that a jail break wasn’t enough action.  It did nothing for the movie and the run time certainly didn’t need it.  The second thing was the conflict generated by the fleet only having 18 hours of fuel.  I understand the role that ticking clocks can have in generating tension in film.  This scenario just didn’t make sense.  I’m willing to forgive the question about where the rest of the Imp- First Order fleet was.  I can even explain away the inability to micro jump.  18 hours doesn’t seem nearly enough time for Finn and Rose to go find this computer guy and bring him back.  I know hyper speed is faster than warp drive, it just doesn’t seem reasonable that they could have ever expected to fulfill the mission and get back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now lets leave the negativity behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought &lt;em&gt;The Last Jedi&lt;/em&gt; was a stunningly beautiful film.  In particular, having the star cruiser hyper speed through Snoke’s command ship was amazing to watch.  Rian Johnson’s decision to cut audio was inspired.  Imp- First Order crafts have never had such a sense of depth as when Finn and Rose infiltrated it.  Similarly, Snoke’s chamber provided a intimidating, alien environment that echoed the intensity of the Luke and Vader duel in the Cloud City Carbonite Chamber in &lt;em&gt;Empire&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Johnson’s writing powered the saga forward by ignoring as much of the J.J. Abrams setup as they possibly could.  Revealing Rey’s parentage to be completely unimportant was the best possible outcome, any other decision would have been seen as servicing some strange corner of the fandom (though, maybe if we didn’t spend so much time obsessing about it, the writers could just write).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The execution of Snoke by Kylo Ren set up the concluding film nicely while paying off two more plot points.  The first being the identity of Snoke.  Once again, not everything needs to be something else.  He didn’t need to be a previous Sith Lord.  All he had to be was evil: Mission Accomplished!  Finally, where are the Knights of Ren?  What are the Knights of Ren?  They’re just gone now.  No need to even bring them up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
	Parameters:
		content - the text
		type - optional type information
		title - optional title information
--&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;post_script alert&quot;&gt;
	
		&lt;div class=&quot;box-header&quot;&gt;
			Post Script
		&lt;/div&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&quot;alert_content&quot;&gt;
		
I was so very, very wrong in my last post.  Really missed the mark.

	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A poorly written review of The Last Jedi. Hashtag salesmanship.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The 75th Annual Golden Globes</title><link href="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/01/06/75th-annual-golden-globes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The 75th Annual Golden Globes" /><published>2018-01-06T13:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-06T13:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/01/06/75th-annual-golden-globes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/01/06/75th-annual-golden-globes.html">&lt;p&gt;The Golden Globes are tonight and, while I haven’t seen a lot of films this year, this does seem to be a good opportunity to share my thoughts on what films I have seen who were nominated.  Needless to say: Spoilers Abound&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Darkest Hour&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I both enjoyed watching and didn’t understand why &lt;em&gt;Darkest Hour&lt;/em&gt;, the story of Winston Churchill’s ascension to Prime Minister of the United Kingdom and the first few weeks in the position, was made in the first place.  I can ignore the historical inaccuracies and enjoy Gary Oldman’s performance with ease.  Similarly, the cinematography and set design were superb.  Throughout the film the audience gets dragged through the scenery with such vigor I think there may still be a bit of muck from the streets in my shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thereafter, I run out of positive things to say.  The narrative is loosely held together by Churchill as a character, but never clearly coalesces.  Early on Lily James is introduces as Elizabeth Layton, Churchill’s secretary, and enters into a character arc from intimidated girl to surrogate daughter.  The transformation ends up being emotionally underwhelming.  Briefly, there is some hope that concerns of infidelity will drive the plot when Kristen Scott Thomas presents a toast to Churchill that is astoundingly chilly, but that was not to be.  The relationship with King George VI, similarly warms without a clear understanding as to why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, it may be that &lt;em&gt;Darkest Hour&lt;/em&gt; exists because some producer wanted to see Gary Oldman recite Churchill’s “We shall fight on the beaches” speech.  Which was wonderful to watch, however it will unlikely be enough to net any prizes, including one for Oldman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Get Out&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversely, &lt;em&gt;Get Out&lt;/em&gt; was a wonderfully crafted narrative that kept me on the edge of my seat from beginning to end.  Throughout the entire film Jordan Peele’s introduced characters and situations causing the audience to question what exactly was in store for both Daniel Kaluuya’s Chris Washington and themselves.  In particular, a brief encounter with Stephen Root sets up several options for concluding the story that eventually resolve in the third act.  Allison Williams steps into the role of Rose easily and provides just enough of a peek through the veneer of sanity to keep the character believable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the wake of it’s release and critical success a large corpus of work discussing the films portray of the African-American experience has been produced.  Speaking intelligently on this matter is beyond my qualifications and the reader is encouraged to seek out more competent reviewers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, &lt;em&gt;Get Out&lt;/em&gt; was an unexpected delight to view.  Given the challenging year in the Drama category, &lt;em&gt;Get Out&lt;/em&gt; stands a good chance of wining the Musical or Comedy field, despite it being neither.  It’s chief rival will be &lt;em&gt;The Disaster Artist&lt;/em&gt;.  Finally, it’s a tragedy that Jordan Peele was not nominated for Best Screenplay&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Shape of Water&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guillermo del Toro’s “not an Abe Sapien origin story” was the most beautiful film I’ve seen in quite some time.  The set design was a breathtaking marriage of 50’s cinema, art deco, and fantasy.  Utterly captivating.  The cinematography had realism that reminded me of the indie films of the 90’s that I found easy to be lost in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite not having a single line Doug Jones gave an emotional performance which perfectly mirrored Sally Hawkins as a mute custodian.  Supported by Michael Shannon, the eternal G Man, &lt;em&gt;The Shape of Water&lt;/em&gt; was perhaps the most balanced film of the year.  Part comedy, part romance, part thriller, it was a movie that any adult could walk into and find something to love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having not seen any of the other nominees for Best Actress, I can’t gauge Sally Hawkins chances, but I also can’t imagine another nominee bringing such emotional breadth to the role.  Up against &lt;em&gt;Dunkirk&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Post&lt;/em&gt; it’s unlikely that del Toro will walk away with a Best Director or Drama award, but has a good chance of taking Screenplay as consolation prize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Baby Driver&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Baby Driver&lt;/em&gt; was the best film I saw all year.  After exiting &lt;em&gt;Antman&lt;/em&gt;, Edgar Wright wrote and directed as engaging and thrilling a heist film as I’ve ever seen.  The characters, the music, the action, the dialogue come together perfectly building a heart pounding film that even the romance scenes supported.  A single nomination of Ansel Elgort for his role as the eponymous hero was positively criminal.  In my books this film should have been nominated for Best Film, Best Original Screenplay, Best Director, and Best Supporting Actor.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Golden Globes are tonight, let's try to predict the future. Because that goes well.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Don’t Be Afraid to Suck</title><link href="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/01/06/dont-be-afraid-to-suck.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Don't Be Afraid to Suck" /><published>2018-01-06T13:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-06T13:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/01/06/dont-be-afraid-to-suck</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/01/06/dont-be-afraid-to-suck.html">&lt;p&gt;Now is a phenomenal time to be a maker.  It doesn’t even matter what it is you’re making.  Coming from a background as a software engineers I know people who have spent years in development on indy games or apps looking to make their mark on the world.  Snapchat filters… I know a guy who built that app a year before Snap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meat space, hacker spaces like TechShop (more on that in another post) have allowed people to start businesses they wouldn’t have had any other way to get going.  Square… the mobile payment platform, that started because the founder went into a hacker space and prototyped the first unit to sell to investors.  Literally all it takes is a little elbow grease and some belief in yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently a number of comedians I’ve been following for ten years have separated from the comedy site they’ve been working for just as long.  Here are personal favorites that are really worth checking out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;you_tube_container&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yfrmm_Fey_I&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;video&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;you_tube_container&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aVhwbS-_SJ4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;video&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;you_tube_container&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LO2bHcbyKyY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;video&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I had to stop here, I also recommend &lt;i&gt;Obsessive Pop Culture Disorder&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;em&gt;CrackedTV&lt;/em&gt;, and just the entire rest of the Cracked video library.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sheer volume and diversity that this team of artists put out was absolutely staggering. Their most recent series, &lt;em&gt;Some News&lt;/em&gt;, deserves special recognition as one of the best satirical news shows of the year, often besting &lt;em&gt;The Daily Show&lt;/em&gt;.  And if you’ve never had a conversation in a coffee shop that reminds you of an &lt;em&gt;After Hours&lt;/em&gt; episode, then I don’t know how you’ve wasted your life this badly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since their exit though, I’ve been inspired every day watching these guys.    &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/drmistercody&quot;&gt;Cody Johnson&lt;/a&gt; continues to comment on politics of the day, building a voice as an articulate and seemingly non-partisan member of the resistance.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dob_inc&quot;&gt;Daniel O’Brien&lt;/a&gt; set up a night of comedy with the Cracked alumni and is among the most positive people to ever live.  A dinner between Daniel O’Brien and Lin-Manuel Miranda would end with them splitting the check by paying for each other’s meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/swaim_corp&quot;&gt;Michael Swaim&lt;/a&gt; has been the breakout story this month.  I’m not going to try to tell &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/posts/why-i-left-by-15727831&quot;&gt;his story&lt;/a&gt; and it is absolutely worth listening to.  In the past month he’s build a Patreon community called &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/swaim_corp&quot;&gt;Small Beans&lt;/a&gt; producing podcasts with pledges in excess of $4,000 a month, of which I am a proud contributor.  It’s been an absolute joy watching this come together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brother is the funniest person I know.  Among our friends and family he’s the funniest person any of us know.  You are probably unaware of it, but &lt;em&gt;JFK&lt;/em&gt; - Oliver Stone’s film about the Kennedy assassination conspiracy - is a comedy.  And it’s pure gold beginning to end.  My brother should be famous.  And were he to get on social media he could be doing great things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for me, it’s time for me to get back into the App Development game and put out some independent stuff.  Not even stuff for other people.  If I’m the only customer that’s fine.  Makers should be their first customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to be Adam Savage to be a maker.  All you have to do is sit down and make something.  Experience the joy of building something from scratch that didn’t exist before.  You don’t have to be perfect.  Try.  Fail.  Try again.  There’s a warm feeling of fulfillment that comes with making something, even if that something is a blog post you don’t actually believe anyone will read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last thing, in addition to the comedians linked above check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/johncheese&quot;&gt;John Cheese&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kawillert&quot;&gt;Katie Willert&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/posts/why-i-left-by-15727831&quot;&gt;Katy Stoll&lt;/a&gt;.  They’re also wonderful Cracked alumni who are worth following and I look forward to seeing what comes next.  I don’t know any of these guys, but, through their work, I’ve had breakfast with them every day for years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
	Parameters:
		content - the text
		type - optional type information
		title - optional title information
--&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;post_script alert&quot;&gt;
	
		&lt;div class=&quot;box-header&quot;&gt;
			Post Script
		&lt;/div&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&quot;alert_content&quot;&gt;
		
All of those videos have NSFW language.  This probably should have been a &quot;Pre Script&quot; ... that can't be right, that's not a thing.

	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A love letter to some of the makers out there.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Donald Trump is President</title><link href="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/01/05/why-donald-trump-is-president.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Donald Trump is President" /><published>2018-01-05T13:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-05T13:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/01/05/why-donald-trump-is-president</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/01/05/why-donald-trump-is-president.html">&lt;p&gt;Earlier today a friend of mine asked me how we ended up here.  By which he meant, how did we end up with Donald Trump as President.  I gave him an answer in three words: Democrats don’t vote.  That’s difficult to hear, but it is, however unfortunately, the truth.  Let’s back up a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reasonable people are able to discuss taxes and the role of government in a civil manner.  National security was effectively guaranteed by the large oceans on either coast, providing a degree of freedom in other &lt;em&gt;realpolitik&lt;/em&gt; applications of international affairs.  These policies accounted for the bulwark of Republican policy since the administration of Teddy Roosevelt.  However, following the election of his cousin Franklin, the GOP only controlled Congress for 4 years cumulatively heading into the election of 1980.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1980 Ronald Reagan became the fourth President of the United States to unseat an incumbent in the 20th century.  There were a number of issues working in Reagan’s favor: The Iran Hostage Crisis, intermittently energy crises, and economic stagnation being a few.  Critically though, Reagan championed two key concepts for the Republican cause that may still be familiar: Supply Side Economics and the Evangelical Right.  Reagan’s courtship of the Evangelicals represented the final migration of the former southern Democrats into the Republican caucus following President Johnson’s signing of the 1964 Voting Rights Act, wherein he prophesied that the Democratic party would lose the South for a generation.  Effectively the Democratic and Republican parties has switched polarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Republican Party entrenched themselves in the Christian Right and the South at large by beginning to champion two specific policies.  The first was support of a strict constructionist interpretation of the Second Amendment, firearm ownership without limit.  The second being a strict opposition to abortion.  The constitutional and moral arguments for these policies were far less important than the overwhelming concern for these two tentpole issues among southern voters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the Republican party would continue to present low taxes, small government, and national security as the public face of Republican policy, these goals often took a back seat to abortion rights and gun control. Reagan first lowered taxes and then raising them amid recession to be reelected in 1984 by the largest electoral college victory since Washington.  From 1981 until 2018, the GOP would control the Senate and House for 18 of 36 years.  The critical observation, however is that since the Congressional redistricting in 1992 the House of Representatives has been Republican for 18 of 24 years.  Additionally, as of 2018, thirty two state legislatures are Republican controlled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fundamentalist constituencies represented by the pro-life and pro-gun lobbies can be swayed by any perceived threat to their position.  Most recently in the Alabama Senate special election, Democrat Doug Jones narrowly defeated an accused child molester.  Despite believing the accusations against Senator Jones’ opponent a significant portion of the electorate continued to opposed Jones because of his position on abortion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reliability of voters to show up can easily be illustrated by the state of Texas.  Not only do Democrats in Texas show up in larger numbers during Presidential elections, they also show up in a larger percentage.  If every Texan who voted for Hillary Clinton were to vote in 2018, not only would Texas be controlled by a Democrat during redistricting in 2020, but I would no longer have to look at Ted Cruz’s face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;caption&gt;Someone explain to me why the governor of Texas is a Republican.&lt;/caption&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Year&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Position&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Republican Votes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Democratic Votes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2016&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;President&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4,685,047 (52.23%)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3,877,868 (43.24%)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Governor&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2,796,547 (59.3%)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,835,596 (38.9%)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2012&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;President&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4,569,843 (57.17%)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3,308,124 (41.38%)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2010&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Governor&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2,737,481 (55.0%)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2,106,395 (42.3%)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2008&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;President&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4,479,328 (55.39%)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3,528,633 (43.63%)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A smart person once said that “decisions are made by those who show up”.  Year after year the fundamentalist base of the Republican party shows up to support their two issues.  Democrats are less likely to participate in elections on off cycle years.  At the end of the day Donald Trump is President because too many voters who were opposed to Donald Trump stayed home on election day.  They were too certain that he would lose.  Next time there’s an election, please show up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, don’t vote for Jill Stein.  I’m looking at you Michigan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
	Parameters:
		content - the text
		type - optional type information
		title - optional title information
--&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;post_script alert&quot;&gt;
	
		&lt;div class=&quot;box-header&quot;&gt;
			Post Script
		&lt;/div&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&quot;alert_content&quot;&gt;
		
How weird is it that Bill Clinton, George W. Bush, and Donald Trump were all born in 1946?

	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A rundown of the underlying cause of how Donald Trump became President.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Mad Mad Mad World</title><link href="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/01/04/a-mad-mad-mad-world.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Mad Mad Mad World" /><published>2018-01-04T13:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-04T13:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/01/04/a-mad-mad-mad-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/01/04/a-mad-mad-mad-world.html">&lt;p&gt;We’re about a year into the Trump Presidency.  Needless to say there’s much about the situation that the United States finds itself in currently that I object to.  Writing on the eve of the release of &lt;em&gt;Fire and Fury&lt;/em&gt;, the embattled Trump administration once again finds itself under a much deserved assault.  Given the past year, I wanted to share my thoughts about what Trump’s impact on the 2020 race may be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Trump Chooses To Not Run&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By far the most likely event is that Donald Trump chooses to not run for reelection.  By all accounts he doesn’t want to be President, he never wanted it, and, most importantly, he doesn’t enjoy it.  Running for President is an exercise in branding, an endeavor that President Trump has shown a unique ability.  Beyond that the President has little interest in the office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to see President Trump announcing that he doesn’t appreciate the way he’s been treated and attempt to bow out prior to the primaries.  It wouldn’t be completely unsurprising, out of malice or incompetence, to withdraw from the race after the filing deadlines had passed which would result in a brokered national convention for the Republican party.  This would allow party elders to select a more stable, controllable candidate and mitigate any fatigue voters may have with the current administration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The GOP Supports Trump As Nominee&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, GOP support for the President isn’t certain, but it is likely.  In this scenario the party leaders have to attempt to manage the Congressional  candidates in an effort to minimize the a strong anti-Trump push from the President’s opponents.  Given Orrin Hatch’s recent decision to retire from the Senate it’s entirely possible that Mitt Romney will emerge as the leader of the mainstream GOP with a concentration on traditional fiscal conservatism to defend the Legislative branch while expecting to lose the Executive branch.  Much in the same way Paul Ryan told congressional candidates to worry about their own races late in the 2016 election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Trump Loses the Nomination&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The power of incumbency is strong, but it’s entirely possible that the President may lose to a primary challenger.  A traditional, mainstream Republican may end up with the nomination leaving the President out in the cold.  From this point there are two possibilities, the preferable one being that President Trump chooses to go gently into that good night.  Thereby sparing a nation desperate to heal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, the President may again harness the forces of chaos and attempt to run as an independent.  While, again, the power of incumbency is strong, the key to victory as an independent will be organization, never a strong suit for the Trump White House.  Getting on the ballot in every state as an independent is difficult without a party to support you.  It’s entirely possible that the President gets on the ballot in a majority of states, but splitting the right wing vote with the GOP backed candidate results in a sweeping Democratic victory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The GOP Rebels Against Trump As Nominee&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nightmare scenario for the Democratic party is that the President wins nomination, but a moderate group from within the GOP elects to run a third party candidate.  While they will not have incumbency to aid their effort, as long term party members with experience organizing across the nation it’s very possible that they could leverage disapproval with the President to get a candidate on the ballots of a vast majority of states (I could easily see anyone to the left of the President being too liberal for Arizona or Alabama).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this situation the strength of the Democratic candidate becomes critical.  Moderate Republicans and independents may remain unwilling to vote for a Democratic candidate given another viable option, not merely a protest vote.  Combine that with a potential “Jill Stein Wins 10,000 Votes In Michigan” situation, now the race is a toss up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should any candidate fail to receive the required 270 electoral college votes, the election will go to the House of Representatives voting by State, not member.  Even if they GOP does not control a majority of the House, due to large populations in California, New York, and Florida, it’s entirely possible that they would control a majority of state delegations.  Remember that as of the time of publication 32 state houses are controlled by the GOP.  Given the choice between a generic Democrat or Donald Trump, it is uncertain if enough GOP state delegations defect to vote a Democrat into the presidency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Trump Is Unavailable to Run&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, there is the possibility, however unlikely that Donald Trump is unavailable to run due to changes in his health or legal status.  In this case a full Republican Primary is run.  Hopefully with more predictable, sane results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
	Parameters:
		content - the text
		type - optional type information
		title - optional title information
--&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;post_script alert&quot;&gt;
	
		&lt;div class=&quot;box-header&quot;&gt;
			Post Script
		&lt;/div&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&quot;alert_content&quot;&gt;
		
It's important to maintain respect for the office.  That's what I keep telling myself.

	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">One year into the Trump Presidency, let's try to predict the future. Because that goes well.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Polentz Ramble</title><link href="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/01/03/polentz-ramble.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Polentz Ramble" /><published>2018-01-03T13:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-01-03T13:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/01/03/polentz-ramble</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://dpfannenstiel.github.io/2018/01/03/polentz-ramble.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve volunteered to run a Promethean game for my RPG group as our regular  storyteller got a little worn out after running game for a year.  That’s rough to do.  And the Storyteller System games is a tough rule set to keep in your head.  I’ve run games before and so I was happy to do it.  Actually, I’m certain that everyone else in the group has run, but I volunteered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Promethean is a fun game and very different within the Chronicles of Darkness series.  It’s the only one that can have a happy ending.  The player characters are artificial life forms in the style of Frankenstein’s monster.  They’re created from dead, or never living, matter and, through “the divine fire”, made life.  From that point they’re on a quest to become mortal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It allows for a really simple and immersive experience.  The characters, over the course of the chronicle, they need to learn what it is to be human.  It’s the simple things like making a friend or creating original art.  Things we take for granted.  It’s really wonderful, they’re a blank slate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of that blank slate is that they usually come into the world in horrible ways.  For another story I had created a character that was a Promethean to wage war against the owners of the plantation he was created on; from pieces of deceased slaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I run the game I’m slowly incorporating elements of the world so that the players and I don’t have to immediately understand the entirety of the world.  Since this is also a horror game, I decided to write up part of the biography for that old character, called his “ramble”, and presented it to the characters.  Enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;I remember not just the beginning. But before the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;I remember the man lashing my own kin to the tree and unfurling the whip. I remember thunder erupting from his hand. Over and over and over. My kin was strong from a life time of hunting in his homeland. And the rope was poorly tied. He might have broken free, but not for the creature. The creature held the rope tight as my kin suffered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;When next my kin was tied to the tree it was by the neck and the creature held his feet. The creature quieted the screams of my kin as they were ravaged. My kin were but babes, torn from the breast of their mothers. Skulls smashed against the stone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;I saw it all. And for all of it the creature was there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;Before my eyes, one became ten became a hundred became a thousand. They died screaming. For all of it the creature was there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;And then it became my turn. The thunder exploded around me. Through me. Again and again. And my eyes opened and I saw her. A tiny little woman, looking of my kin, with her hand raised. I couldn't breath and she saw me panic. She stayed her hand and two of my kin rushed over and cut me down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;And that was how I began.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I've volunteered to run a Promethean game for my RPG group.</summary></entry></feed>